Now here's a turn-up for the books - a film star has been giving away free books on the London Underground.
现在，这可真是一件出乎意料的事情——一位电影明星一直在伦敦地铁上免费赠送书籍。
If you're a bookworm, as well as a Harry Potter fan and a Tube traveller, this month has been exciting for you.
如果你是一个书虫，同时又是《哈利·波特》的粉丝以及伦敦地铁的乘客，那么这个月对你来说可真是令人兴奋。
Emma Watson, who starred in films based on the novels about a fictional schoolboy wizard, has been hiding books on the Tube for passengers to leaf through.
艾玛·沃特森曾主演了根据一部基于虚构的男学生巫师的小说改编的电影，她一直在伦敦地铁上藏一些书，供乘客们翻阅。
It's part of the Books On The Underground movement, which has a simple aim: to get more people burying themselves in literature.
这是“地铁上的书”活动的一部分，该活动有一个简单的目标：让更多的人沉浸于文学之中。
And the way they do it is to leave tomes on trains for commuters to pick up, dip into and then leave for another lucky reader to skim.
他们的做法是把大部头的书留在火车上，让通勤者捡起来，翻阅一下，然后再留给另一位幸运的读者浏览。
The movement started out in 2012 and drops off about 150 volumes a week in stations across the UK's capital.
这个活动始于2012年，每周会在英国首都的各个地铁站放置大约150册书。
Talking about Watson's participation in the project, the manager of Books On The Underground, Cordelia Oxley, said, "The reaction has been phenomenal.
谈到沃特森对这个项目的参与，“地铁上的书”活动的经理科迪莉亚·奥克斯利说：“反响非常惊人。
It must be a mixture of how much everyone adores Emma, and how exciting it is to find something as wonderful as a new book on your journey."
这肯定是因为大家都非常喜欢艾玛，以及在旅途中发现像一本新书这样美妙的东西是多么令人兴奋。”
The 100 or so editions Watson left for passengers to pore over were even more special because she left a hand-written inscription.
沃特森留下供乘客仔细研读的大约100本书籍更加特别，因为她留下了手写的题词。
The paperbacks were copies of Maya Angelou's Mom & Me & Mom.
这些平装书是玛雅·安杰卢的《妈妈、我和妈妈》。
One person who discovered a copy of the book on the Tube said she felt like the character Charlie Bucket - a boy who finds a golden ticket to the world's greatest chocolate factory - in the Roald Dahl classic, Charlie and the Chocolate Factory.
一位在地铁上发现这本书的人说，她感觉自己就像罗尔德·达尔的经典作品《查理和巧克力工厂》中的角色查理·巴克特-一个找到进入世界上最伟大的巧克力工厂的金票的男孩。
Watson became a UN Women Goodwill Ambassador in the summer of 2014 and has since started devouring as many books and essays on equality and feminism as possible.
沃特森在2014年夏天成为了联合国妇女署亲善大使，从那以后，她开始尽可能多地阅读关于平等和女权主义的书籍和文章。
She has also started her own book club.
她还创办了自己的读书俱乐部。
So, why not take a leaf out of Emma Watson's book and leave a copy of your favourite book on a train?
那么，为什么不效仿艾玛·沃特森，把你最喜欢的一本书留在火车上呢？
It could make a stranger's life richer.
这可能会让一个陌生人的生活更加丰富多彩。